nmnknwr@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/namankanwar/ +1-470-263-0059 naman26.github.io

Professional Summary

Recent graduate with 3+ years of experience in data analysis, data mining, data visualization and machine learning. Extensive experience in working with multi-disciplinary teams, applying data insights to diverse fields, generating reports and interactive dashboards for stakeholders. Seeking opportunities to leverage data skills in a collaborative environment.

Education

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science in Computer Science - CS: 3.56 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - CS: 4.0 Aug 2019 — Jul 2020 Jun 2016 — Jul 2019

Skills

- Languages: Java (Proficient), Python (Proficient), C++ (Proficient), Javascript
- Database and Visualization: MariaDB, Oracle, PostgreSQL, AWS Lambda, Amazon (QuickSight, Sagemaker, S3), Kibana, Tableau, Folium, Plotly
- · Concepts: Object-oriented programming, Mobile development, MVC, Agile/Scrum, Multithreading, ETL, Data Analysis, Data Mining
- Other: Spring Boot, Linux, UNIX, Windows (PowerShell), Git, Flask, Selenium

Experience

Georgia State EBCS Atlanta, GA

Evidence Based Cyber Security Group - Data Engineer

Aug 2019 – Aug 2020

- Developed web scrapers to collect data from suspicious websites. Engineered CAPTCHA breaking system with 90% accuracy rate to automate the scrapers.
- Created automatic weekly business report, empowering institute-wide policy decisions using Python, Selenium, SQL and folium.
- Coordinated with the associate director to maintain and develop EBCS website (ebcs.gsu.edu). Onboarded and handed project to incoming developer.

Fiserv Atlanta, GA

Global Finance Solution - Software Development Engineer Intern

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Worked on 35,000+ lines of Java code with no existing documentation. Wrote documentation for existing and newly added code.
- o Automated database server shutdown and creation, saving 12% annual costs.

Georgia State CS Department

Atlanta, GA

Computer Science Department - Data Engineer

Oct 2017 - Aug 2019

- Implemented an algorithm that visualizes evolutionary trees using Python. Reduced the execution time of current algorithm by 99%.
- Designed an API along with a full stack website architecture to deploy the algorithm.
- Integrated interactive visualization of data using D3.js. Completed and deployed the website within 4 months which is being used by hundreds of biologists.

Verizon Connect Atlanta, GA

Fleetmatics - Data Analyst

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- o Directly increased userbase by 20% utilizing data mining techniques for analysis.
- o Built analytics dashboards from Hive tables using Java to depict user driving behavior.
- o Utilized Apache Spark to develop data analytics for business intelligence and product development.

Project Hermes Atlanta, GA HackGT 19 - WINNER Aug 2019

o Implemented a Google Maps feature (Google Maps API and Places API) in Android app to map 3 locations in 1 route. Project URL: github.com/Naman26/HermesOCR

CS Music Atlanta, GA

Collegiate Cup 2019

Jan 2019

o Devised the code sharing aspect for an AR Android application to help 52% low income kids learn computer science. Project URL: github.com/Naman26/CSMusic

PharmaPal Atlanta, GA

HackATL 18 - WINNER

Oct 2018

 Designed a computer vision Android app that takes a picture of medication and obtains information and instructions about the drug in 2 seconds using text-to-speech API, translate API, and server programming.

Visitr Atlanta, GA

HackGSU 17 - WINNER

May 2017

o Engineered a voice-controlled check-in and check-out Echo Skill utilizing Twilio API. Project URL: github.com/Naman26/Anthem-Visitor-Alexa-Skill

Anthropocene Atlanta, GA

2D- Platformer Game

May 2017

o Produced a 2D Platformer game that illustrates how dependence on technology is initiating climate change. Project URL: github.com/Naman26/Game-Anthropocene

Certifications

HackerRank

HackerRank

Java Developer Credentials: hackerrank.com/certificates/4f83321244ab

Aug 2020

Python Developer Credentials: hackerrank.com/certificates/540a2bdaaf11

Aug 2020

Other

Leadership

Georgia State University

- o Association of Computing Machinery: Chair http://acm.cs.gsu.edu/
- o Georgia State CS Department: Teaching Assistant Discrete Mathematics, Data Structures, Software Engineering

Awards

4+ National Hackathon Awards

- o HackGT: 2019: Optical Character Challenge Runner-Up
- o HackGSU: 2019: 1st in Crypto challenge, 2017: Anthem Grand Prize
- o HackATL: 2018: Health and Wellness Challenge Runner-Up
- o Georgia State University: 2018: Outstanding Undergraduate Research Award